<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>https://auerl.github.io on https://auerl.github.io</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in https://auerl.github.io on https://auerl.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2.5D Waveform Inversion</title>
      <link>/project/25d-wfi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/25d-wfi/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3d-to-2d-data-transformations&#34;&gt;3D-to-2D Data Transformations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seismic full waveform inversion is often based on forward modelling in the
computationally attractive 2-D domain. Any solution of the 2-D cartesian wave
equation inherently carries the assumption of being generated by a line source,
extended in the out-of-plane direction, implying that source energy spreads over
the surface of a cylinder, and that amplitudes scale with one over square-root
of distance. However, realistic point sources like explosives or airguns, fired
in a 3-D medium, generate amplitudes that decay with one over distance, since
the wavefield expands spherically in all three dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, geophysicists correct for this amplitude difference and the associated
phase shift of π/4 by transforming recorded field data to approximate 2-D, using
simplistic asymptotic filter algorithms, operating on a time-sample basis and
assuming straight ray paths and a constant velocity medium. The sometimes
careless usage of these filters, is in contradiction to their well known
limitations. I could show that filtering errors are moderate in purely acoustic
situations but become substantial in complex media when arrivals overlap each
other or ray paths deviate strongly from straight lines. Normalized
root-mean-square deviations up to 5 % and maximum relative time domain errors up
to 40 % were found in high contrast media, when full elastic treatment is
considered. See doi: 10.1190/geo2012-0382.1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-5-d-full-waveform-tomography&#34;&gt;2.5-D Full Waveform Tomography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of my Masters thesis I investiagted potential of 2.5-D frequency-domain
finite-element modelling of seismic wave propagation, which is based on Fourier
transforming the 3-D wave equation along the invariant axis to
frequency-wavenumber domain and solving the resulting equation for many
wavenumber components,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thus breaking down the 3-D problem to a large number of 2-D problems. An attempt
is made to circumvent problems associated with singularities in the wavenumber
spectrum by combining a finite-element 2.5-D forward solver and a
complex-frequency extension. By shifting the poles off the real axis, they are
avoided in the inverse Fourier transform to the frequency domain. I could show
that problems associated with the singularities are mitigated and the total
number of required wavenumber samples is significantly reduced, as soon as
frequencies are allowed to be complex. Reconstructed finite-element 2.5-D
seismograms compare very well to reference finite-difference 3-D seismograms.
2.5-D modelling with complex frequencies outperforms asymptotic 3D-to-2D
transformation showing very low misfits between 2.5-D and 3-D synthetics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animating data with Unity</title>
      <link>/project/football-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/football-animation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At TRACKTICS we are constantly trying to come up with new ways to visualize the
  data our customers acquire with their Trackers. Here&amp;rsquo;s a small example of how
  Unity can be used to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe
src=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Ftracktics%2Fvideos%2F1073790999445342%2F&amp;show_text=0&amp;width=476&#34;
width=&#34;476&#34; height=&#34;476&#34; style=&#34;border:none;overflow:hidden&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;
frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowTransparency=&#34;true&#34; allowFullScreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://reportage2.stuttgarter-zeitung.de/fussball-digitalisierung&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://reportage2.stuttgarter-zeitung.de/fussball-digitalisierung&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data analysis pipeline</title>
      <link>/project/data-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/data-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This repository contains a set of infrastructure tools to deploy, operate and develop the so called TRACKTICS Pipeline. The TRACKTICS Pipeline is a framework that allows to orchestrate parallel DAG (Direct Acyclic Graphs) batch processing jobs. It is based on Docker for artifact deployment, ECS (Amazon EC2 Container Service) for container orchestration and resource discovery, Luigi (by Spotify) for workflow and dependency management, SQS (Amazon Simple Queuing System) as a job queue, a custom autoscaler, S3 and Postgres (Amazon RDS) to store results and Kinesis to for logging. On a service level our toolbox features a universal Python wrapper that allows to expose the functionality of each service to ECS and the workflow manager, in a consistent way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global seismic anisotropy</title>
      <link>/project/global-anisotropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/global-anisotropy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;global-anisotropy&#34;&gt;Global anisotropy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, me and colleagues at UPMC Paris (Lapo Boschi), USC Los Angeles
(Thorsten Becker) and University of Oxford (Tarje Nissen-Meyer), have developed
a new global model of anisotropic shear-velocity variations, called savani,
which represents one of the first attempts to map anisotropic wavespeeds at the
scale of the entire mantle. While being well correlated with earlier models at
long spatial wavelength, our preferred solution, savani, additionally delineates
a number of previously unidentified structures, due to its improved resolution
in areas of dense coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because the density of the inverse grid ranges between 1.25 ◦ in well
sampled to 5◦ in poorly sampled regions, allowing us to resolve regional
structure better than it is typically the case in global S-wave tomography.
Important features of our model include: (i) A distinct ocean-continent
anisotropic signature in the uppermost mantle; (ii) an oceanic peak in above
average ξ &amp;gt; 1 which is shallower than in previous models and thus in better
agreement with estimates of lithosphere thickness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See a publication about savani at doi:10.1002/2013JB010773 and feel free to
download our model and documentation via&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;broadband-tomography&#34;&gt;Broadband tomography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my thesis I have presented the theoretical and methological foundations of a
new global waveform tomography approach, with the rationale to keep approximate
(ray) theory where appropriate (global long-wavelength structure, surface wave
dispersion), but to revert to a full-waveform interpretation where necessary
(regional scale, non-geometrical wave phenomena). Finite-frequency kernels are
being calculated via the spectral element solver AxiSEM (Nissen-Meyer et al.
2014) and a new code called MCkernel (co-developed with Simon Stähler and Martin
van Driel). Overall, our method will provide straightforward framework to
stepwise improve upon a global background model by re-inverting an updated
linear system whenever new (types of) data become available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oceanic-upper-mantle&#34;&gt;Oceanic upper mantle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defining the oceanic lithosphere as a thermal boundary layer allows to explain,
to first order, age-dependent bathymetry and isotropic wavespeeds. In contrast,
SS precursors and receiver functions suggest a subhorizontal interface within
this layer, on top of a radially anisotropic zone. Comparing a suite of
geodynamic scenarios against surface-wave dispersion data and seismic
discontinuties we find that only weak age dependency of the radially anisotropic
zone is compatible with observations. We show that this zone is confined from
below by a second, weaker seismic interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While azimuthal anisotropy is consistent with LPO of olivine due to
asthenospheric flow underneath the lithosphere, radial anisotropy requires
additional contributions, perhaps from petrological fabrics or melt ponding.
This implies that seismic reflectors previously associated with the base of the
lithosphere are instead associated with preserved structures embedded in it.
They carry information about plate formation, but have little control on plate
deformation. See doi:10.1002/2015GL066246.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter quake detection</title>
      <link>/project/cloudquake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cloudquake/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermal structure, radial anisotropy, and dynamics of oceanic boundary layers</title>
      <link>/publication/doi-10-1002-2015-gl-066246/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/doi-10-1002-2015-gl-066246/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AxiSEM: broadband 3-D seismic wavefields in axisymmetric media</title>
      <link>/publication/doi-10-5194-se-5-425-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/doi-10-5194-se-5-425-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mantle dynamics in the Mediterranean</title>
      <link>/publication/doi-10-1002-2013-rg-000444/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/doi-10-1002-2013-rg-000444/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Savani: A variable resolution whole-mantle model of anisotropic shear velocity variations based on multiple data sets</title>
      <link>/publication/doi-10-1002-2013-jb-010773/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/doi-10-1002-2013-jb-010773/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A critical appraisal of asymptotic 3D-to-2D data transformation in full-waveform seismic crosshole tomography</title>
      <link>/publication/doi-10-1190-geo-2012-0382-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/doi-10-1190-geo-2012-0382-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
