<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>https://auerl.github.io on https://auerl.github.io</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in https://auerl.github.io on https://auerl.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a scalable batch processing pipeline for sensor fusion using Docker, Luigi, ECS and S3</title>
      <link>/post/tracktics-data-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 23:05:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tracktics-data-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!---

## Introduction 

- Describe the problem

## Our Solution

- Insipration blog posts

### Architecture overview

- Sketch of TRACKTICS architecture

### Workflow Management

- Luigi vs. Airflow vs. 
- Directed Acyclic Graphs

### Container Orchestration

- ECS vs Kubernetes vs Fargate

### Continuous Integration

- Testing approach
- 
--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Q-Learning with PyTorch and the Unity ML-Agents Toolkit</title>
      <link>/post/deep-reinforcement-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 23:05:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deep-reinforcement-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!---

## Introduction

- How I got interested in the topic: The AI &amp; Games conference
--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animating data with Unity</title>
      <link>/project/football-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/football-animation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tracktics.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TRACKTICS&lt;/a&gt; we are constantly trying to come up with new ways to visualize the
data that our customers acquire with their GPS Performance Trackers. Recently, we have devised a
prototype feature of visualizing Location and Attitude data in the form of
three-dimensional animations using the Unity 3D engine. Here&amp;rsquo;s a small example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe
src=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Ftracktics%2Fvideos%2F1073790999445342%2F&amp;show_text=0&amp;width=476&#34;
width=&#34;476&#34; height=&#34;476&#34; style=&#34;border:none;overflow:hidden&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;
frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowTransparency=&#34;true&#34; allowFullScreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The visualization has been featured in a Report by &lt;a href=&#34;https://reportage2.stuttgarter-zeitung.de/fussball-digitalisierung&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stuttgarter
Zeitung&lt;/a&gt;
and might be turned into a new feature for TRACKTIC&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.tracktics.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Web
App&lt;/a&gt; feature (using Unity&amp;rsquo;s built tools for WebGL).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data analysis pipeline</title>
      <link>/project/data-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/data-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The TRACKTICS Pipeline is a framework that allows to orchestrate parallel DAG
(Direct Acyclic Graphs) batch processing jobs. It is based on Docker for
artifact deployment, ECS (Amazon EC2 Container Service) for container
orchestration and resource discovery, Luigi (by Spotify) for workflow and
dependency management, SQS (Amazon Simple Queuing System) as a job queue, a
custom autoscaler, S3 and Postgres (Amazon RDS) to store results and Kinesis
to for logging. On a service level our toolbox features a universal Python
wrapper that allows to expose the functionality of each service to ECS and
the workflow manager, in a consistent way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global seismic anisotropy</title>
      <link>/project/global-anisotropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/global-anisotropy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;global-anisotropy-savani&#34;&gt;Global anisotropy (SAVANI)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together with colleagues at UPMC Paris (&lt;a href=&#34;http://hestia.lgs.jussieu.fr/~boschil/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lapo
Boschi&lt;/a&gt;), USC Los Angeles
(&lt;a href=&#34;http://www-udc.ig.utexas.edu/external/becker/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Thorsten Becker&lt;/a&gt;) and
University of Oxford (&lt;a href=&#34;http://seis.earth.ox.ac.uk/people/tarje.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tarje
Nissen-Meyer&lt;/a&gt;),
have developed a new global model of anisotropic shear-velocity variations, called SAVANI,
which represents one of the first attempts to map anisotropic wavespeeds at the
scale of the entire mantle. While being well correlated with earlier models at
long spatial wavelength, our preferred solution, savani, additionally delineates
a number of previously unidentified structures, due to its improved resolution
in areas of dense coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because the density of the inverse grid ranges between 1.25° in well
sampled to 5° in poorly sampled regions, allowing us to resolve regional
structure better than it is typically the case in global S-wave tomography.
Important features of our model include: (i) A distinct ocean-continent
anisotropic signature in the uppermost mantle; (ii) an oceanic peak in above
average ξ &amp;gt; 1 which is shallower than in previous models and thus in better
agreement with estimates of lithosphere thickness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;age-dependency.jpg&#34; width=500&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find more details about SAVANI and its construction in &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/2013JB010773&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Auer et al. 2014&lt;/a&gt;. Also, feel free to
download our model and documentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/auerl/savani&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;from my
GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, if you want to use the model for
your own work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oceanic-upper-mantle&#34;&gt;Oceanic upper mantle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defining the oceanic lithosphere as a thermal boundary layer allows to explain,
to first order, age-dependent bathymetry and isotropic wavespeeds. In contrast,
SS precursors and receiver functions suggest a subhorizontal interface within
this layer, on top of a radially anisotropic zone. Comparing a suite of
geodynamic scenarios against surface-wave dispersion data and seismic
discontinuties we find that only weak age dependency of the radially anisotropic
zone is compatible with observations. We show that this zone is confined from
below by a second, weaker seismic interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;upper-mantle.png&#34; width=500&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While azimuthal anisotropy is consistent with LPO of olivine due to
asthenospheric flow underneath the lithosphere, radial anisotropy requires
additional contributions, perhaps from petrological fabrics or melt ponding.
This implies that seismic reflectors previously associated with the base of the
lithosphere are instead associated with preserved structures embedded in it.
They carry information about plate formation, but have little control on plate
deformation. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/2015GL066246&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Auer et al. 2015&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-for-global-tomography&#34;&gt;Software for global tomography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my PhD I developed and contributed to several tools for global
tomographic imaging, some of which are publicly available. See:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;petscinv-a-general-purpose-parallel-tomography-solver-based-on-petsc&#34;&gt;PETScinv - A general purpose parallel tomography solver based on PETSc&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PETScinv is a modular, general purpose tomography solver written in (object
oriented) Fortran 2008. PETScinv solves global tomographic imaging problems
in parallel using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcs.anl.gov/petsc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PETSc&lt;/a&gt; component
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcs.anl.gov/petsc/petsc-current/docs/manualpages/KSP/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;KSP&lt;/a&gt;.
The scalable linear equations solvers
(KSP) module provides an easy-to-use interface to the combination of a Krylov
subspace iterative method and a preconditioner (in the KSP and PC components,
respectively) or a sequential direct solver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code currently only supports orthogonal, curvilinear hexahedral basis
functions (spherical sections or voxels), but adding modules to treat other
parametization strategies (splines, spherical harmonics, wavelets) to discretize
the model space, should be straightforward. One can account for different
regularization approaches, such as roughness minimization or norm minimization.
Tomography results can be exported in a simple ASCII format or as netcdf files,
together with an .xdmf file, ready to be explored with ParaView. Get the code
via my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/auerl/petscinv.git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;flexinv-ray-theoretical-surface-and-body-wave-sensitivity-kernels&#34;&gt;FLEXinv - Ray-theoretical surface and body wave sensitivity kernels&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flexinv is a Fortran/Python toolbox to create global, adaptive resolution
transversely isotropic tomographic models of the entire mantle, via joint
inversion of surface-wave dispersion and body-wave traveltimes, in the
high-frequency ray approximation. See &lt;it&gt;Auer et al. (2014)&lt;/it&gt; and &lt;it&gt;Boschi (2009)&lt;/it&gt;
for a complete description of the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some components of the surface wave parts of this code go back to &lt;em&gt;Woodhouse
(1981)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Dziewonski &amp;amp; Anderson (1981)&lt;/em&gt;. The body-wave routines go back to
&lt;em&gt;Gu (2005)&lt;/em&gt;. Crustal corrections are based on CRUST2.0 by &lt;em&gt;Laske et al. (2002)&lt;/em&gt;.
Models are parameterized in curvilinear hexahedrons, whose size is adapted
to local ray coverage, following &lt;em&gt;Schäfer et al. (2011)&lt;/em&gt;. Get the code
via my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/auerl/flexinv.git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;mckernel-broadband-waveform-sensitivity-kernels-for-seismic-tomography&#34;&gt;MCkernel - Broadband waveform sensitivity kernels for seismic tomography&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MCkernel is a software implementation to calculate seismic sensitivity kernels
on arbitrary tetrahedral or hexahedral grids across the whole observable seismic
frequency band. These kernels rely on wavefield databases computed via AxiSEM
(www.axisem.info), and thus on spherically symmetric models. The advantage is
that frequencies up to 0.2 Hz and higher can be accessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the usage of irregular, adapted grids is an integral part of
regularisation in seismic tomography, MCkernel works in a inversion-grid-centred
fashion: A Monte-Carlo integration method is used to project the kernel onto
each basis function, which allows to control the desired precision of the kernel
estimation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it means that the code concentrates calculation effort on regions of
interest without prior assumptions on the kernel shape. The code makes extensive
use of redundancies in calculating kernels for different receivers or
frequency-pass-bands for one earthquake, to facilitate its usage in large-scale
global seismic tomography. MCkernel is available &lt;a href=&#34;http://seismology.github.io/mc_kernel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sprint age dependency</title>
      <link>/project/sprint-age-dependency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/sprint-age-dependency/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;age-dependency-of-sprint-top-speeds&#34;&gt;Age-dependency of sprint top speeds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRACKTICS is having a long-term partnership with Fundación Real Madrid Clinics
(FRMC) where we equip hundreds of football schools under the Real Madrid Brand
Umbrella with our GPS performance trackers. In the scope of this partnership we have
collected performance data of tens of thousands of youth players, which amounts
to what we think is probably the largest data set of its kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the Real Madrid dataset we have devised a new model of sprint top speed
age-dependency, using simple restricted cubic spline regression (see the figure above).
While we have used the resulting model in the scope of our partnership with FRMC
we have not yet got the time to wrap up the model in a publication, which would
be interesting for a larger audience, as our model is probably the most
extensive modelling attempt of sprint top speed age-dependency ever conducted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter sentiment analysis</title>
      <link>/project/cloudquake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cloudquake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CloudQuake is a university project where I tried to apply real-time sentiment analysis on Twitter
streams. Our approach was to first collect data via Amazon Kinesis (which allows
for a convenient way to combine data from different sources) and then use Apache
Spark Realtime and its MLlib to classify tweets using a simple Naive Bayes
classifier trained with publicly available annotations. While the initial idea
was to first filter the data for earthquake related tweets and then combine the
inferred tweet sentiments with a Long/Short term moving average indicator with
the goal to detect whether the mentions of Quake-related tweets allow to detect
earthquakes. The detection didn&amp;rsquo;t prove to be stable probably owed to the
relatively limited amount of tweets that is provided by the Twitters free Api.
So all is left is a nice Twitter sentiment analysis engine ;-). The code is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/auerl/cqsent&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;available&lt;/a&gt; on my GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waveform Tomography</title>
      <link>/project/waveform-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/waveform-imaging/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;full-waveform-tomography&#34;&gt;Full Waveform Tomography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seismic Full Waveform Tomography has been one of my main interests since my
thesis supervisor Prof. Stewart Greenhalgh has introduced me to the
topic during the final year of my Master&amp;rsquo;s studies in 2011. Full waveform
tomography describes an inverse modeling approach, where information encoded in
subtle variations in seismic and acoustic waveforms that have traversed
complex media, are mapped back into structural images of the subsurface at
scales from medical imaging applications up to dimensions of the whole earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the core of these methods lie, on one hand, compute intensive forward problems
where the seismic or acoustic wave equation is solved to compute &amp;ldquo;sensitivity
kernels&amp;rdquo; (essentially reverse mapping functions from waveform or traveltime
differences to structure) as well as a large-scale optimization problems, where
the sensitivity kernels are used to reconstruct structural models of wave
speeds or other physical parameters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been a plethora of approaches to solve these problems, pursuing
different strategies to compute sensitivity kernels (time domain, frequency
domain, approximate methods, full-wave methods) and to solve the inverse problem
(conjugate gradient methods, hessian based methods, &amp;hellip;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While during my &lt;a href=&#34;https://auerl.github.io/downloads/msc_thesis.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MSc thesis&lt;/a&gt; I
worked on frequency-domain waveform inversion on the exploration (and near surface)
scale, during my &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3929/ethz-a-010715830&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PhD thesis&lt;/a&gt; I focused on
methods for whole-earth imaging. In this context I have developed a waveform
based imaging method for global tomographiy imaging that is called &amp;ldquo;Broadband
Tomography&amp;rdquo; and combines infinite-frequency ray theory for the surface wave
portions of the seismogram, with finite-frequency kernels for the body wave
portion of the seismic record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3d-to-2d-data-transformations&#34;&gt;3D-to-2D Data Transformations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first project in the area of full waveform tomography has been during my MSc
thesis where I was investigating detrimental effect of common 3D-to-2D data
transformations on frequency domain FWI. This is important because seismic full
waveform inversion is often  based on forward modelling in the
computationally attractive 2-D domain. Any solution of the 2-D cartesian wave
equation inherently carries the assumption of being generated by a line source,
extended in the out-of-plane direction, implying that source energy spreads over
the surface of a cylinder, and that amplitudes scale with one over square-root
of distance. However, realistic point sources like explosives or airguns, fired
in a 3-D medium, generate amplitudes that decay with one over distance, since
the wavefield expands spherically in all three dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, geophysicists correct for this amplitude difference and the associated
phase shift of π/4 by transforming recorded field data to approximate 2-D, using
simplistic asymptotic filter algorithms, operating on a time-sample basis and
assuming straight ray paths and a constant velocity medium. The sometimes
careless usage of these filters, is in contradiction to their well known
limitations. Comparing simulated data using a FDTD forward solver
for visco-elastic seismic wave propagation in 3D and 2D media, we could show
that filtering errors are moderate in purely acoustic situations but become
substantial in complex media when arrivals overlap each
other or ray paths deviate strongly from straight lines. Normalized
root-mean-square deviations up to 5% and maximum relative time domain errors up
to 40% were found in high contrast media, when full elastic treatment is
considered. We published our results in &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1190/geo2012-0382.1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Auer et al. 2013&lt;/a&gt;.
Also feel free to download my &lt;a href=&#34;https://auerl.github.io/downloads/msc_thesis_auer.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;thesis&lt;/a&gt;
or a pdf of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://auerl.github.io/downloads/msc_talk_auer.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;thesis presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-5-d-full-waveform-tomography&#34;&gt;2.5-D Full Waveform Tomography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motivated by the questionable performance of the aforementioned 3D-to-2D filters
the second chapter of my thesis investiagted potential of 2.5-D frequency-domain
finite-element modelling of seismic wave propagation, which is based on Fourier
transforming the 3-D wave equation along the invariant axis to
frequency-wavenumber  domain and solving the resulting equation for many
wavenumber components, thus breaking down the 3-D problem to a large number of
2-D problems. In my thesis I made an attempt to circumvent problems associated
with singularities in the wavenumber spectrum by combining a finite-element
2.5-D forward solver and a complex-frequency extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;wavenumber-spectrum.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By shifting the poles off the real axis, they are avoided in the inverse Fourier
transform to the frequency domain. I could show that problems associated
with the singularities are mitigated and the total
number of required wavenumber samples is significantly reduced, as soon as
frequencies are allowed to be complex. Reconstructed finite-element 2.5-D
seismograms compare very well to reference finite-difference 3-D seismograms.
2.5-D modelling with complex frequencies outperforms asymptotic 3D-to-2D
transformation showing very low misfits between 2.5-D and 3-D synthetics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;broadband-finite-frequency-kernels&#34;&gt;Broadband Finite Frequency Kernels&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While tomographic imaging of global anisotropy was with few exceptions still
using ray theoretic methods. In my &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3929/ethz-a-010715830&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PhD
thesis&lt;/a&gt;
I have presented the theoretical and methological foundations of a new global
waveform tomography approach, with the rationale to keep approximate (ray) theory where appropriate (global long-
wavelength structure, surface wavedispersion), but to revert to a full-waveform
interpretation where necessary (regional scale, non-geometrical wave phenomena).
Finite-frequency kernels are being calculated via the spectral element solver
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/geodynamics/axisem&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AxiSEM&lt;/a&gt; (Nissen-Meyer et al. 2014) and a new code called
&lt;a href=&#34;http://seismology.github.io/mc_kernel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MCkernel&lt;/a&gt;.
Our imaging method provides a framework to stepwise improve upon a global
background model by re-inverting an updated linear system whenever new (types
of) data become available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;waveform-kernels.png&#34; width=500&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The huge advantage of using numerical methods to compute banana donought kernels
as shown in the above figure is that while wave theory breaks down for
non-geometrical wave phenomena like Core-diffractions, spectral-element based FF
kernels can account for the complex interactions at the core mantle boundary and
thus allow imaging those interesting regions of the earths mantle with higher
accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;predicted-deltat.png&#34; width=500&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My PhD thesis can be downloaded
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3929/ethz-a-010715830&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
Also find my thesis presentation under &lt;a href=&#34;https://auerl.github.io/downloads/phd_talk_auer.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermal structure, radial anisotropy, and dynamics of oceanic boundary layers</title>
      <link>/publication/doi-10-1002-2015-gl-066246/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/doi-10-1002-2015-gl-066246/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AxiSEM: broadband 3-D seismic wavefields in axisymmetric media</title>
      <link>/publication/doi-10-5194-se-5-425-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/doi-10-5194-se-5-425-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mantle dynamics in the Mediterranean</title>
      <link>/publication/doi-10-1002-2013-rg-000444/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/doi-10-1002-2013-rg-000444/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Savani: A variable resolution whole-mantle model of anisotropic shear velocity variations based on multiple data sets</title>
      <link>/publication/doi-10-1002-2013-jb-010773/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/doi-10-1002-2013-jb-010773/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A critical appraisal of asymptotic 3D-to-2D data transformation in full-waveform seismic crosshole tomography</title>
      <link>/publication/doi-10-1190-geo-2012-0382-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/doi-10-1190-geo-2012-0382-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
