<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on https://auerl.github.io</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on https://auerl.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Animating data with Unity</title>
      <link>/project/football-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/football-animation/</guid>
      <description>At TRACKTICS we are constantly trying to come up with new ways to visualize the data that our customers acquire with their GPS Performance Trackers. Recently, I created a small prototype, visualizing locations and orientation (yaw angle) time series data in the form of three-dimensional animations using the Unity 3D engine. Here&amp;rsquo;s a small example:
 The visualization has been featured in a Report by Stuttgarter Zeitung and might be turned into a new feature for TRACKTIC&amp;rsquo;s Web App feature - not decided yet, though ;-).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data analysis pipeline</title>
      <link>/project/data-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/data-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>The TRACKTICS Pipeline is a framework that allows to orchestrate parallel DAG (Direct Acyclic Graphs) batch processing jobs. It is based on Docker for artifact deployment, ECS (Amazon EC2 Container Service) for container orchestration and resource discovery, Luigi (by Spotify) for workflow and dependency management, SQS (Amazon Simple Queuing System) as a job queue, a custom service for auto scaling, S3 and Postgres (Amazon RDS) to store results and Kinesis for logging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global seismic anisotropy</title>
      <link>/project/global-anisotropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/global-anisotropy/</guid>
      <description>Global anisotropy (SAVANI) Together with colleagues at UPMC Paris (Lapo Boschi), USC Los Angeles (Thorsten Becker) and University of Oxford (Tarje Nissen-Meyer), have developed a new global model of anisotropic shear-velocity variations, called SAVANI, which represents one of the first attempts to map anisotropic wavespeeds at the scale of the entire mantle. While being well correlated with earlier models at long spatial wavelength, our preferred solution, savani, additionally delineates a number of previously unidentified structures, due to its improved resolution in areas of dense coverage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sprint age dependency</title>
      <link>/project/sprint-age-dependency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/sprint-age-dependency/</guid>
      <description>Age-dependency of sprint top speeds TRACKTICS is having a long-term partnership with Fundación Real Madrid Clinics (FRMC) where we equip hundreds of football schools under the Real Madrid Brand Umbrella with our GPS performance trackers. In the scope of this partnership we have collected performance data of tens of thousands of youth players, which amounts to what we think is probably the largest data set of its kind.
Based on the Real Madrid dataset we have devised a new model of sprint top speed age-dependency, using simple restricted cubic spline regression (see the figure above).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter sentiment analysis</title>
      <link>/project/cloudquake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cloudquake/</guid>
      <description>CloudQuake is a university project where I tried to apply real-time sentiment analysis on Twitter streams. Our approach was to first collect data via Amazon Kinesis (which allows for a convenient way to combine data from different sources) and then use Apache Spark Realtime and its MLlib to classify tweets using a simple Naive Bayes classifier trained with publicly available annotations. While the initial idea was to first filter the data for earthquake related tweets and then combine the inferred tweet sentiments with a Long/Short term moving average indicator with the goal to detect whether the mentions of Quake-related tweets allow to detect earthquakes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waveform Tomography</title>
      <link>/project/waveform-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/waveform-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Full Waveform Tomography Seismic Full Waveform Tomography has been one of my main interests since my thesis supervisor Prof. Stewart Greenhalgh has introduced me to the topic during the final year of my Master&amp;rsquo;s studies in 2011. Full waveform tomography describes an inverse modeling approach, where information encoded in subtle variations in seismic and acoustic waveforms that have traversed complex media, are mapped back into structural images of the subsurface at scales from medical imaging applications up to dimensions of the whole earth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>