<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on https://auerl.github.io</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on https://auerl.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2.5D Waveform Inversion</title>
      <link>/project/25d-wfi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/25d-wfi/</guid>
      <description>3D-to-2D Data Transformations Seismic full waveform inversion is often based on forward modelling in the computationally attractive 2-D domain. Any solution of the 2-D cartesian wave equation inherently carries the assumption of being generated by a line source, extended in the out-of-plane direction, implying that source energy spreads over the surface of a cylinder, and that amplitudes scale with one over square-root of distance. However, realistic point sources like explosives or airguns, fired in a 3-D medium, generate amplitudes that decay with one over distance, since the wavefield expands spherically in all three dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animating data with Unity</title>
      <link>/project/football-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/football-animation/</guid>
      <description>At TRACKTICS we are constantly trying to come up with new ways to visualize the data our customers acquire with their Trackers. Here&amp;rsquo;s a small example of how Unity can be used to
 https://reportage2.stuttgarter-zeitung.de/fussball-digitalisierung</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data analysis pipeline</title>
      <link>/project/data-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/data-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>This repository contains a set of infrastructure tools to deploy, operate and develop the so called TRACKTICS Pipeline. The TRACKTICS Pipeline is a framework that allows to orchestrate parallel DAG (Direct Acyclic Graphs) batch processing jobs. It is based on Docker for artifact deployment, ECS (Amazon EC2 Container Service) for container orchestration and resource discovery, Luigi (by Spotify) for workflow and dependency management, SQS (Amazon Simple Queuing System) as a job queue, a custom autoscaler, S3 and Postgres (Amazon RDS) to store results and Kinesis to for logging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global seismic anisotropy</title>
      <link>/project/global-anisotropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/global-anisotropy/</guid>
      <description>Global anisotropy Recently, me and colleagues at UPMC Paris (Lapo Boschi), USC Los Angeles (Thorsten Becker) and University of Oxford (Tarje Nissen-Meyer), have developed a new global model of anisotropic shear-velocity variations, called savani, which represents one of the first attempts to map anisotropic wavespeeds at the scale of the entire mantle. While being well correlated with earlier models at long spatial wavelength, our preferred solution, savani, additionally delineates a number of previously unidentified structures, due to its improved resolution in areas of dense coverage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter quake detection</title>
      <link>/project/cloudquake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cloudquake/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>